A Finding Aid to the Dimitri Hadzi Papers, 1910s-2007, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Audiovisual Material, 1952-2000; Series 13; Archival Resource Key; 12 Linear feet Box 26-40
  - Documentaries, Archival Resource Key
    - Dimitri Hadzi Works in Black Wax, 1952; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 74)
      Note on reel: PROJECTION RM 2B-63, DO NOT REMOVED DIMITRI WORKS IN BLACK WAX. Tail leader: Dimitri End Pict P. Holander. There is a VHS copy of this film housed with the collection.
    - Dimitri Hadzi Works in Black Wax, Negative, 1952; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 75)
      Note on reel: DIMITRI WORKS IN BLACK WAX. Head leader: "DIMITRI" HEAD PIX. Tail leader: DIMITRI END PICT P. HOLANDER. K-463 J-7588 (crossed out) ORIG NEG PICTURE (sync point) R1 "DIMITRI-WORKS-IN-BLACK-WAX" KINESIS - INC. There is a VHS copy of this film housed with the collection.
    - Dimitri Hadzi Works in Black Wax, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Dimitri Hadzi: American Sculptor, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Events and Exhibitions, Archival Resource Key
    - Richard Gray Gallery Exhibition, ca. 1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 76)
      Note on film can: TRIANGLE CHI-GRAY. On side of can: RICH GRAY GALLERY HADZI EXH N.G. PRINT. Note: possible shot list. Head leader: G4555 Hadzid
    - Richard Gray Gallery Exhibition, Negative, ca. 1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 77)
      Note on can: R GRAY EXHIBITION NEGS, MAY BE OTHER MATERIAL NEG. Head leader: G 4555 HADZID
    - Tyler Exhibition Reel 1, 1969; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 78)
      Note on can: C-39Z TYLER, Dimitri (illegible). Printing order form included. Tail leader: DIMITRI HADZI C-39Z TYLER ORD 1427 2X30.
    - Tyler Exhibition Reel 2, 1969; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 79)
      Note on film can: TYLER EXHIBITION, TYLER EXH, (Illegible), BRACCIANO - SCULPTORS LUNCHEON DIMITRI 77222. Inside can lid: (illegible) 1-8-72. Head leader: Mr G DIMITRI - Ord. 17222
    - Tyler Exhibition, Negative, 1969; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 80)
      Lab label on can: CLIENTE: HADZI DIMITRI, Soggetto: TYLER EXHIBITION, Data: 1-8-72, Ordinativo 17222. Head leader: Mr G DIMITRI ord. 17222. This reel is the negative for "Tyler Exhibition" can 2.
    - Unknown Exhibition, 1971; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 81)
      Note on can: PLASTER DIVIDED DIVISO Desmantel, Mold Maker. 4307, B4, B6, B7, 1307, 1,4594, (Illegable numbers). Sticker: 131-2-32-4-52-6-7 16 MUCH TO BE CUT!!! (crossed out), (NICCI) Rossi, Muzi. Chalk on side of film roll: MOSTRA MONOLI 6/12/71 NEG 13370. Head leader: DIMITRI HADZI MOSTRA ORD 13370.
    - Professor Sekler Lecture, 1972 October 12; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Fullerton College, Arcturus Unveiling Ceremony, 1974 April 19; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 7 inch (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Fullerton College, Lecture, 1974 April 19; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 7 inch (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Hadzi Lecture, 1975 December 9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Hadzi Dedication, 1982 May 20; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Dimitri Hadzi: A Retrospective View, Owens-Illinois, Inc., Toledo, Ohio, 1982 August 14; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Dimitri Hadzi: A Retrospective View, Owens-Illinois, Inc., Toledo, Ohio; Open House, 1982 September 24; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (U-matic) (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Dimitri Hadzi: A Retrospective View, Owens-Illinois, Inc., Toledo, Ohio, 1982; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 73)
      Note on film shipping container: HADZI OPTICAL OWENS - ILLINOIS PROPYLAG. Head leader: GTN OWENS ILLINOIS FS382 "DIMITRI HADZI: A RETROSPECTIVE VIEW" FCC #66127 82-241 5-14-82 HEAD. Tail leader: GENERAL TELEVISION NETWORK OWENS ILLINOIS FS382 "DIMITRI HADZI: A RETROSPECTIVE VIEW" FCC #66127 82-241 5-14-82 TAIL. There is a U-Matic copy of this film housed with the collection.
    - Dimitri Hadzi (Work Print), 1995 January 11; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Works on Paper: Dimitri Hadzi; Opening, 1997 March 1; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Retrospective; Copley Place Fountain, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Munich; Exhibition, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Foundries, Archival Resource Key
    - Nicci Foundry, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 63)
    - Nicci Foundry; Rome Studio; WGBG GBArts; Johnson Foundry, circa 1967-1999; Archival Resource Key; 2 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Nicci Foundry; Driving Sounds; Postman Singing; Dinner with Christina, 1968 September; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Foundry Sounds; Driving, 1968 September; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Nicci Foundry #4; Lucio; Choral Music, 1968 September; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Nicci Foundry, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Nicci Foundry, Trims and Outtakes, 1950-1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 60)
    - Arcturus; Francesco Bruni Foundry, 1972 July; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Francesco Bruni Foundry, 1972; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 61)
    - Francesco Bruni Foundry Negative, 1972; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 62)
    - Nicci Foundry, 1999 May; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Russi/Nicci Foundry, Wax Burnout Pour, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Box 36)
      - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, Untitled 1, reel 1, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 53)
      - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, Untitled 2, reel 2, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 54)
      - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, Untitled 3, reel 3, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 55)
      - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, Untitled 4, reel 4, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 56)
      - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, Untitled 5, reel 5, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 57)
      - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, Untitled 6, reel 6, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 58)
      - Unknown Foundry Trims and Outtakes, Untitled 7, reel 7, 1950-1980; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 59)
  - Hadzi and Others, Archival Resource Key
    - Hadzi Monoprinting, 1995 March 31; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Hadzi and Nina, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Dimitri Hadzi; A. Elsen; Off Line Edit, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Lipschitz, 1972 August; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Henry Moore, 1972; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Vincent Scully, 1976 April 21; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Henry Moore Interview; Simons, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Tuckwell; Moore (Simons), undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Moore; Jacobi, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Noguchi, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound cassette (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Octetra by Isamu Noguchi, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 82)
      Note on can: SPOLETO '68, JUNE 25 29 (circle) (5205). B 16 - (DART) BUCKY FULLER, NOGUCHI, BERMAN, MOLLY. B 17 - NOGUCHI DUOMO SCULPTURE LUNCHEN. B18 NOGUCHI, RUSSEL HARRIS AND PRISCILLA MORGAN. VIEWED MAR 9 '93, VERY GOOD FOOTAGE DEDICATION, ETC. - PLENTY OK KIDS PLAYING IN/ON SCULPTURE.
    - Simons (Zajac), undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Sculptor's Lunch, 1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 83)
      Note on can: (illegible word) Sculptors (illegible words), Upside down (illegible words). Laboratory order form. Tail leader: ORD H 278 HADZI DIMITRI JFK.
  - Projects and Installations, Archival Resource Key
    - Thermopylae; Terra III, circa 1966; Archival Resource Key; 2 Film reels 16mm
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston and Terra III, reel 1, 1966; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 69)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston and Terra III, reel 2, 1966; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 70)
    - Terra III, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 2 Film reels 16mm
      - Terra III, reel 1, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 71)
      - Terra III, reel 2, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 72)
    - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, 1967-1968; Archival Resource Key; 5 Film reels 16mm
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston Negative, reel 1, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 66)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston Negative, reel 2, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 65)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston Negative, reel 3, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 64)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston Negative, reel 4, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 67)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston Negative, reel 5, 1967; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 68)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 1, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 84)
        Note on can: JFK - PRINT DATES? INSTALLED - MANY VIEWS, ETC. F 99, APRZ 99 JFK PRINT, INSTALLED - LONG SHOTS/CLOSE - UPS - BAND PLAYING (Illegible)?, SHOT OF MOLLY IN CAR/CHRISTINA/(illegible). Tail leader: Dimitri Hadzi JFK 1- JFK 2 - JFK 3 ORD H 189
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 2, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 85)
        Note on box: MICROSTAMPA and an address. On other side of box: SHOOT AT 80 WP/G FILTER (crossed out).
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 3, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 86)
        Note on can: 2, COPY FROM REVERSAL 6259, REVERSIBLE FILM, SUBJECTS:, NO:, CONTRO TIPO, ? Not in Proj. Order, Dimitri ord 6259, ON REEL, NOTE: EMULSION IS ON THE OUTSIDE (?). Head leader: Dimitri Boston ord 6393. Tail leader: DIMITRI HADZI JK BOSTON ORD 6393. Paired with Installations/Thermopylae/JFK Boston Negative Can 3 of 5.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 4, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 87)
        Note on can: Numbers that correspond to possible shot list, (illegible note), NO REEL, Numbers that do correspond to shot list included in can. TACLIO ROSSI (written in red wax pencil). On side of can: same numbers that correspond to shot list in can.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 5, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 88)
        Note on can: 1, COPY FROM REVERSIBLE FILM, SUBJECTS:, NO:, CONTRUTIPO, ?, 6393, Dimitri ord 6393, APR '99, 1/2 SCALE PLASTER AT DIMENTEL - WORKING ON IT WITH MAQUGITO - DISMANTELING + TO TRUCK, YARD + DOG. Note in can: Lab order form. Head leader: DIMITRI BOSTON ORD 6259. Tail leader: SIG DIMITRI J.K. BOSTON ORD 6259.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 6, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 89)
        Note on can: Numbers that correspond to possible shot list, (illegible note), NO REEL, Numbers that do correspond to shot list included in can. TACLIO ROSSI (written in red wax pencil). On side of can: same numbers that correspond to shot list in can. Tail leader: DIMITRI A-70-1-71/A 72Z ORD 2916.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 7, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 90)
        Note on can: Letters and numbers relating to a possible shot list, NICCI FOUNDRY POURING SEQUENCE (ON REEL). Two illegible notes included.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 8, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 91)
        Note on can: REEL, ROSSI/MUZI MOLD MKE. MUZI - MOLD MKG SPHERE, PROJECTED OCT 11 '93 D/H. TAGLIO R (circle) SERIES. Note on reel: Mold Making, ROSSI - MUZI MOLD MAKE, (illegible) Reel tails. Head leader: DIMITRI BH6 - H7 - H8, ORD 5 (illegible) 96. Tail leader: DIMITRI B44 - 45 ORD 5424.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 9, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 92)
        Note on can: DIMITRI, DA DIVIDERE, TACLIARE, 18 + 19 (?) rewind for projection
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 10, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 93)
        Note on film can: JFK COLOR, JFK - COLOR, AT ROSSI'S ROME.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 11, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 94)
        Note on can: No. 93 '68, (illegible) #11 copy for (crossed out) Reversal Neg made also. 120' (illegible) Neg, Test Roll FM 12 (circled) (illegible and crossed out). Note on reel: RAGGED EDGE CAREFUL! Head leader: DIMITRI (crossed out) MIMITRI. Tail leader: S.E.K Boston ORD h 876. In the original housing, a trim was included with a note, "#13 Beginning of roll". The trim has been rehoused in "Thermopylae/JFK Boston Trims and Outtakes" Can 13 of 18.
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Reel 12, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 95)
        Note on box: JFK BOSTON, B-58 NICCI, COLOR AUG 8, 1968, FURNACES, POURINGS,. ASA 170, DIN 23. B-58 COLOR. Other side of box: B-52 COLOR, 2. ((223 (illegible), 300 d223/m (illegible) 300/m (illegible)(all crossed out)). Note on film can: JFK BOSTON B. 58 NICCI FNDY, furnaces, pouring, (illegible). Aug. 8 1968 (T 3 zook) EF Ektachrome 7242. ((CHARGE TO D. HADZI, (illegible) 82 (crossed out))
    - Thermopylae, JFK Boston; Arcturus, 1972; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 97)
      Note on can: OLD BOLEX - MINN ROME ARCTURUS. Side of can: ARCTURUS BIRKERTS ROME MANOLIS. Possible shot list included. Head leader: DIMITRI old Bolex MINN ord 17225.
    - Thermopylae, JFK Boston; Arcturus, Negative, 1972; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 98)
      Lab label on can: CLIENTE: HADZI DIMITRI. Soggetto: OLD BOLEX MINN. Data: 1-8-72. Ordinativo: 17-225. On side of can: OLD-BOLEX-17225. Printing documentation included in can. Head leader: DIMITRI - old Bolex MINN - ord. 17225.
    - Thermopylae; Thecht, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes, Archival Resource Key
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 1, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 109)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 2, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 110)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston Trims and Outtakes reel 3, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 111)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 4, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 112)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 5, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 113)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 6, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 114)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 7, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 115)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 8, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 116)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 9, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 117)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 10, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 118)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 11, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 119)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 12, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 120)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 13, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 121)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 14, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 122)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 15, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 123)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 16, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 124)
      - Thermopylae, JFK Boston, Trims and Outtakes reel 17, 1968; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 125)
    - Thermopylae, JFK Boston; Ecumenical Doors, circa 1960-1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 126)
    - Ecumenical Doors, Negative, 1970; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 127)
    - JFK, Reviewing Rushes; Film Review, 1968 September; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Thermopylae, JFK Film Project, Film Transfers, 1968-1969, 1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Thermopylae, JFK Film Project, Notebook, 1967-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Thermopylae, JFK Film Project, 1999-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Thermopylae, JFK Film Project, 1997-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - St. Paul's Doors outtakes; Minneapolis; Eugene, circa 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 10 Film reels 16 mm
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 1: Unknown, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 42)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 2: Wire Removal, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 43)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 3: Fire Factory, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 44)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 4: Binding, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 45)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 5: Final Smoking, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 46)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 6: Plastering Drums, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 47)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 7: Discs, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 48)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 8: Terra, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 49)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 9: Final, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 50)
      - St. Paul's Door Outtakes, Reel 10: Two Unknown, bulk 1970-1979; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16mm (Item FC 51)
    - Arcturus, 1973; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 96)
      Note on can: VARIE DIMITRI, WA ARCTURUS, WAXES, GESSO
    - Arcturus, Williamette River Oracle, Ecumenical Doors, 1975; Archival Resource Key
      - Arcturus, Williamette River Oracle, Ecumenical Doors, 1 of 2, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 99)
        Note on reel: Tails - foundry. Date taken from documentation for the corresponding negative.
      - Arcturus, Williamette River Oracle, Ecumenical Doors, 2 of 2, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 100)
        Note on reel: S. PAOLO 3, S PAOLO. Tail leader: H. Dimitri - S. Paolo ord. 4047 R 2.
      - Arcturus, Williamette River Oracle, Ecumenical Doors, Negative, 1 of 2, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 101)
        Note on can: Negatives. Lab form. Data: 7-6-75, Ordinativo: 4047. ARCTURUS Tail leader: H Dimitri - S. Paulo ord 4047 - R. 1
      - Arcturus, Williamette River Oracle, Ecumenical Doors, Negative, 2 of 2, 1975; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 102)
        Note on can: Negatives. Lab form. CLIENTE: HADZI DIMITRI, Soggetto: S. PAOLO, Data: 7-8-75, Ordinativo: 4047 ST PAUL (NICCI). Tail leader: H DIMITRI - S. PAOLO, ord 4047 R 2.
    - For the Record, circa 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 52)
      Master Sculptures include Bruce Beasley, Roger Bolomy, Dimitri Hadzi, High Townley, Tony Rosenthal and John Chamberlin. Recorded at the Oregon International Sculpture Symposium in 1976 in Eugene.
    - Eugene Symposium; Springfield Quarry, circa 1973-1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 41)
    - River Legend, 1976; Archival Resource Key
      - River Legend, 1 of 6, 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 103)
        Note on box: JOHNSON WAX/RACING NEG (crossed out) REVERSAL, POSS. RIVER LEGENG. Note on other side of box: JOHNSON WAX RACINE, Hadzi's address.
      - River Legend, 2 of 6, 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 104)
        Note on box: PORTLAND - River Legend. Note on can: Harvard Uni. Carpenter Center, PLUS - X REVERSAL, film specs, Date AUG '76, RIVER LEGEND - EUGENE. CHARGE TO D. HADZI. Sticker: CS35141
      - River Legend, 3 of 6, 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 105)
        Note on box: PORTLAND - River Legend. Note on can: Harvard Uni. Carpenter Center, PLUS - X REVERSAL, film specs, Date AUG '76, RIVER LEGEND - EUGENE. CHARGE TO ME (crossed out) D. HADZI. Sticker: CS 35142
      - River Legend, 4 of 6, 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 106)
        Note on box: PORTLAND - River Legend. Note on can: Harvard Uni. Carpenter Center, PLUS - X REVERSAL, film specs, Date AUG '76, DARK RIVER LEGEND - PORTLAND. CHARGE TO D. HADZI. Sticker: CS 35140.
      - River Legend, 5 of 6, 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 107)
        Note on box: PORTLAND - River Legend. Note on can: Harvard Uni. Carpenter Center, PLUS - X REVERSAL, film specs, Date AUG '76, RIVER LEGEND - PORTLAND INSTALLATION. CHARGE TO D. HADZI. Sticker: CS 35139.
      - River Legend, 6 of 6, 1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel 16 mm (Item FC 108)
        Note on box: PORTLAND - River Legend. Note on can: Harvard Uni. Carpenter Center, PLUS - X REVERSAL, film specs, Date AUG '76, RIVER LEGEND - PORTLAND INSTALLATION. CHARGE TO D. HADZI. Sticker: CS 35138.
    - Bracciano Sculpture; Gil Franklin, Don Acquilno, Paul Suttman, Aldo Casanova, 1970 May 29; Archival Resource Key; 1 Sound tape reel 5 inch (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - Seagate Spectacular and Other Hadzi Display Footage, 1983 November 11; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Fox River Oracle, circa 1985-1990; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Hadzi: In Lowell, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Dimitri Hadzi: Sculpture, 1998 January 7; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (VHS) (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Dimitri Hadzi: Sculpture, 1998 January 7; Archival Resource Key; 5 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 29, Folder 7-10)
    - Dimitri Hadzi: Sculpture, 1998 January 7; Archival Resource Key; 5 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 30, Folder 1-5)
  - Studios, Archival Resource Key
    - Osborne; 1/2 Scale Plaster; Pimentel; Dismantling Trucks, 1999 May; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Pimentel, undated; Archival Resource Key; 1 Videocassettes (BetacamSP) (Box 30, Folder 7)